——FCS工作室校正出品——
“在我们的感官认知之外”
“可能藏着我们从不曾察觉的新世界”
“新世界”
角龙
Diablos!
“我们的世界”
“联合国  联合安全行动”
“北纬33度56分  东经67度42分”
B小队呼叫老鹰
Falcon Main, this is Bravo Team.
B小队呼叫老鹰  有收到吗
Falcon Main, this is Bravo Team. Do you copy?
暴风来袭  能见度零  请求立即支援
Storm incoming. Zero visibility. Request immediate support.
老鹰  这里有异状  请立即支援
Falcon Main, something's in here with us. Send immediate support.
B小队呼叫老鹰  请立即支援
Falcon Main, this is Bravo Team. Send immediate support.
长官…
Ma'am. Ma'am.
-马修 -林克在半公里外有发现
- Marshall. - Link found something half a klick ahead.
-B小队  -应该是
- Bravo Team? - Think so.
艾克斯 史提勒  备好重机枪
Axe. - With Steeler. Man the 50.
-是  老大 -女孩们  准备好
- Yes, boss. All right, ladies. Saddle up.
女军官也还是用那句话来谯人
She's a woman, but she still manages to make that sound like an insult.
早点习惯吧
Get used to it.
上尉  你有看到那些石碑吗
Captain.
看到了
- You see those markers? - Yeah, I see them.
你知道它们是什么吗
Do you have any idea what they are?
戴维斯中士  我是游骑兵  不是考古学家
Sergeant Davis, I'm a Ranger, not an archeologist.
收到
Copy that.
艾克斯
- Axe! - What?
-干嘛  -你在听什么
- What are you listening to?
乔治琼斯的歌
- George Jones.
那是谁啊
Who the hell's that?
-你真没文化  史提勒 -没错
You're a philistine, Steeler. Yes. Yes, I am.
靠  马修  你反应真快
Damn, Marshall. You got hella reflexes.
今天第15只了
Fifteenth casualty today.
-真猛 -格杀勿论  戴维斯
- Killing them. - Take no prisoners, Davis.
-林克  你发现什么  -铁定是B小队
- Link, what'd you find? - It's definitely Bravo Team.
但踪迹到这就没了
But the tracks end here.
-B小队开什么车  -装甲悍马和反伏击车
- What were Bravo Team traveling in? - Up-armored Humvee and a M-ATV.
十吨重的装甲车不会凭空消失
That's ten tons of armored vehicle. They don't just disappear.
老大  有状况
Boss, we've got something.
从12点方向接近中
Incoming. On your 12.
-从哪冒出来的  -突然就有了
- Where did that come from? - Came out of nowhere.
B小队最后的通讯有提到风暴
Bravo Team reported a storm in their last transmission.
-敌方的掩护  -像在阿富汗的埋伏
- Hostiles using it for cover? - An ambush. Like in Helmand?
我们别冒险
Let's not find out.
红色警戒
REDCON-1.
要是敌人躲在风暴后面就刺激了
If there are hostiles hiding behind that storm, things might get kinetic.
收到
Copy that.
马修  你在干嘛
Marshall, what are you doing, bro?
万一我被爆头…
In case I get my head blown off,
他们才能辨别我的身份
they can still tell who I am.
亏你想得出来  混蛋
Hardcore shit, cabrón.
该死
Damn!
可恶  差点就中了
Goddamn, that shit's close.
林克  你看过这种闪电吗
Link, you ever seen lightning like this before?
从来没看过
No. Never.
但我在这装甲车里觉得很安全
But I feel pretty secure here in this big steel box,
还握着好大一把枪
holding my metal gun.
小戴  12点方向  你看那些石碑
Dash, on your 12! Look at those markers!
那是什么东西
What the hell is that?
-小心 -该死
- Watch out! - Damn it!
准备撞击
Brace yourselves!
靠
Shit!
这里是哪里 风暴呢
Where the hell are we? And what happened to the storm?
刚刚发生什么事
What the hell just happened?
-嘿 -你们几个
- Hey! - Guys!
你们还好吗
You okay?
没事
- I'll survive.
我们是被闪电击中
- Did we just get hit by lightning?
-史提勒  你还好吗  -好极了
- Steeler, you good? - Never better.
哪来这么多沙子
Where did all this sand come from?
这一切太不对劲了
This isn't right, none of it.
那是什么
What the hell is that?
这地图没标注任何建筑或山脉
I don't see any structures or mountains marked on this map.
照地图看来…
According to this,
最近的沙丘应该在20公里外
the nearest sand dune is 20 klicks away.
-怎么可能  -这里是哪里
- How's that possible? - Where the hell are we?
-我们怎么离大路这么远  -我不知道
- How did we get so far from the road? - I don't know.
艾克斯  到沙丘上去设个观测点
Axe, get on one of those dunes and set up an observation point.
是
- Yes, boss.
史提勒
- Steeler!
巡逻车能动  它没那么弱
- DPV will run. She's had worse.
-马修  -GPS坏了  老大
- Marshall? - GPS is fried, boss.
无线电跟卫星都没动静  指南针也挂了
Radio and sat. All I get is static. Even the compass is screwed up.
-一定是闪电的关系 -你有什么打算
Must have been the lightning. Well, what do you wanna do?
老方法  靠太阳辨别方向
Go analog. Navigate by the sun.
用走的也要想办法回基地
Make it back to base. We hoof it if we have to.
老大  这要走很久
Boss, that's a long hike.
是啊  走到有通讯为止
Yeah, well, we keep going till we get comms.
空中预警系统会派援兵
Then AWACS will call in support.
开直升机或装甲车过来
They'll send helos, maybe armor.
-好耶 -我们能继续行动了
- Nice. - Back in business.
老大…
- Boss.
-发送讯号吧 -你得看看这个
- Send it. There's something you got to see.
装甲巡逻车和反伏击车
Up-armored DPV and a M-ATV.
是B小队
It's Bravo Team.
以V队形前进
V-formation. Move out.
他们怎么办
What do we do about them?
等有通讯了  再请后援来处理尸体
When we get comms, we'll call in recovery assets to retrieve the bodies.
-他们怎么了  -火焰喷射器
- What happened to them? - Flamethrowers.
我看不是
I don't think so.
火焰喷射器不会把人烧成这样
Never seen a flamethrower do this to a man.
凝固汽油弹的温度都没这么高
- Not even napalm burns that hot.
长官…
- Ma'am?
这是玻璃
It's glass.
-玻璃  -沙子熔化就会变成玻璃
Glass? When sand melts, it turns to glass.
要怎么让沙子熔化
How do you melt sand?
我不知道
I don't know.
这已经超越我的职权范围了
This shit is officially above my pay grade.
他们打了一场硬仗
Looks like they made a stand.
满地都是弹壳
- Let off a lot of rounds. - They didn't hit anything.
什么都没打中  我没看到尸体
There's no bodies.
或许他们把尸体带走了
Maybe they took the bodies with them?
我看过那种事
- I've seen that before.
是啊  问题就在这里
- Yeah. - Well, that's just the thing.
你看到什么  林克
- What do you see, Link?
啥都没有
Nothing.
完全没有踪迹
No tracks anywhere.
对方没留下任何痕迹
Whoever did this, they didn't leave a mark.
我们不能久留  出发
We need to get moving. Move out!
暗星呼叫老鹰…完毕
Dark Star to Falcon. Dark Star to Falcon, over.
该死  闪电真的弄坏电子设备了
Damn it. Lightning really messed up the electronics, huh?
不只是电子设备
Not just electronics.
-什么意思  -很奇怪
- What do you mean? - This isn't right.
这一切都很不对劲
Nothing about this is right.
那道闪电对我们有某种作用
That lightning, it did something to us.
上尉自有判断
Captain knows what she's doing, all right?
听说军中的薪饷香又好
They say that in the army The pay is mighty fine
长官先发一百块  再拿回九十九
They give a hundred dollars And take back 99
我朝思暮想
Oh, how I wanna go
但他们偏不让我
But they won't let me go
回家
Home
听说军中的鞋子材质好
They say that in the army The shoes are mighty fine
你11号的脚  只能穿9号
You ask for size 11 They give you size nine
You ask for size 11 They give you a size nine
我朝思暮想  但他们偏不让我走
Oh, Lord, I wanna go But they won't let me go
天啊
Jesus.
这是恐龙吧
- It has to be a dinosaur, right?
我在博物馆看过恐龙
- Saw a dinosaur in a museum one time.
它可没有这么大
It wasn't that big.
12点方向 300公尺外有敌人
Hostile, 12 o'clock, 300 meters!
停火…
Cease fire! Cease fire!
怎么回事
- What's going on?
这只是石灰粉
- It's just chalk.
老大
Chief?
角龙
Diablos.
六点方向
On our 6!
那是什么玩意
What the hell is that?
林克  回车上
Link, back in the vehicle.
小戴 史提勒  快开车
Dash, Steeler, move, move, move!
开火
Fire!
它快追上来了
It's gaining on us!
你被压住了
You're caught.
-快出来 -不行  一…
- Come on, get out of here! - No way! - One...
-该死… -二 三
- Holy...two, three!
开火
Fire!
快把手给我
Give me your hand. Come on!
小戴  快点
Dash! Come on!
我也想啊
I'm trying!
史提勒
Steeler!
好了…
- Got it, got it, got it!
马修  上车
- Marshall, get in!
我们走吧
Let's go, big boy!
抓住我的手
Give me your hand!
进去
Get inside!
林克  拿火箭筒来
Link, get the RPG!
天啊
Oh, my God.
撤退
Fall back! Fall back!
-快跑 -撤退  快找掩护
Run for cover!
上尉
Captain.
快跑
Come on!
快啊  老大
Come on, boss!
快进去…
I got it, I got it! Move, move!
换弹中
Reloading!
那到底是什么东西
What was that thing? What is that?
我就说那道光把我们带到某个地方
I told you. I told you. That light, it took us somewhere.
我们得想办法回去
We need to get back. We need to get back home.
-冷静点  中士 -天啊  我们会死在这
- Stow it, Sergeant Davis. - Oh, my God. We're gonna die here.
给我闭嘴  士兵  这是命令
Shut that shit up right now, soldier. That's an order.
看看史提勒跟艾克斯的下场
- You see what it did to Steeler and Axe? - Dash, hey.
小戴  我剩三个  你呢
I got three. You?
-什么  -三个弹匣
- What? - Three mags left.
有差吗 你有看到那家伙吗
What does it matter? Did you see that?
有差  因为军人的职责就是战斗
It matters because we're soldiers. And this is what we do. We fight.
-对吧  -游骑兵打头阵
- Am I right? - Rangers lead the way.
-你们要来吗  -当然  老大
- You with me? - Always, boss.
你们都疯了
You're all crazy.
我不管那是什么鬼东西
You know, I don't care what the hell that thing is.
我们要拿出本事 杀出活路
We do what we do best. We fight and we survive.
不管机会有多渺茫  知道吗
No matter what the odds. You got it?
-是  长官 -是  长官
- Yes, ma'am. - Yes, ma'am.
知道吗
You got it?
知道了  长官
Loud and clear, ma'am.
我还剩三个  你呢
Now, I got three left. What about you?
医疗包
Med pack!
-心肺复苏术  马修 -来了
- CPR, Marshall. - On it.
-太迟了 -胡说
- It's too late. - Bullshit!
别放弃  游骑兵  快啊
Don't die on me, Ranger. Come on.
-没脉搏了 -不行  继续试
- Lack of pulse. - Unacceptable. Try it again.
-很抱歉 -靠  还有好几只
- I'm sorry. - Shit! There's more of them!
快  我们得走了
Come on! We have to go!
我们被包围了
They're everywhere!
-抱歉 -士官长
I'm sorry. Master sergeant!
-林克 -好  跟我来
- Link! - All right, on me!
我们快撤
Let's move out!
撤退…
Fall back, fall back!
小戴
Dash!
快点  继续移动
Come on! Keep moving!
马修
Marshall!
快跑…
Go, go, go!
林克  小戴
Link. Dash.
小戴
Dash.
“史蒂芬马修”
“医疗包”
“呼吸用氧气”
快啊
Come on.
-你还活着 -林克
- You're alive. - Link.
怎么了…
What is it? What is it?
我胸痛 手臂发麻
Pain in my chest! I can't feel my arm.
你中毒了
Some sort of poison.
你得等它消退
You just gotta work through it.
我们走  来吧
Come on. Let's move. Come on.
天啊
Oh, God.
糟了
Oh, no.
上尉
Captain.
就在前面而已  我们走
All right, it's just a little further. Let's go.
我动不了了
I can't move.
我看一下怎么回事
Okay, let me see. Let me see what it is.
走开
Go!
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
-天啊  林克 -你快逃
God, Link! No! You gotta go!
林克
Link!
“直到永远”
该死
Damn you.
你们真该死
Damn you!
但我会回家的
But I'm coming home.
影蜘蛛
Nerscylla.
-影蜘蛛 -放开我
- Nerscylla! - Get off me.
你过得很爽嘛…
Nice life you've...
轮到你了吧
See how you like it.
干杯
Cheers.
你这个小气鬼
Oh, you spiteful little bastard.
那这样呢
Hey. How about that?
你不喜欢吧 不好笑了吧
Yeah. You don't like that, huh? Not so funny now, huh?
我要杀了你
I'll kill you.
来吧
Come on!
用力…
Push! Push!
来
Here.
我不是你的敌人
I'm not your enemy.
等等…
Wait, wait.
等等
Wait.
等一下
One second.
你看…
Look. Look.
来
Here.
食物
Food.
这是食物
Food. Here.
拿去
Take it.
给我  你看…
Here, give it to me. Look, look.
很好吃
So good.
好吃吧
It's good, right?
哇
Wow!
慢慢来  很好吃的
Slow down. Okay, it's good.
这是巧克力
It's chocolate.
巧克力
- Chocolate.
-巧克力 -对  巧克力
- Chocolate. Yeah, chocolate.
巧克力
Chocolate.
- Choco... - Chocolate!
我没有巧克力了
- I don't have any more.
没有了  你看…
No, no more, no more, no more. Look, look. Nothing.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
天啊  谢谢你
Oh, my God. Thank you so much.
我的天
Oh, my God.
谢谢你
Thank you.
嘿
Hey.
等等  你要去哪里
Wait! Where are you going?
等等
Wait!
你跟我去那里
Me and you go out there?
对
Yes.
就是那道闪电把我带来的
That lightning, I think that's what brought me here.
我得去那里才能回家
I need to go there. I need to get home.
那家伙还在那里
That thing is still out there.
角龙
- Diablos.
那里…
Hey, over there...
有我的武器
I have weapons.
角龙…
Diablos...
什么
What?
- What?
-影蜘蛛 -不要
- Nerscylla. No.
我们不用再下去了
We don't need to go back in there.
我们得去角龙那里
We need to go out there. Diablos.
-角龙 -角龙
Diablos. Diablos.
影蜘蛛
Nerscylla.
角龙
Diablo...
给它下毒
We poison it.
聪明
Smart.
只有魔物才杀得了魔物
To kill a monster, you need a monster.
可是要怎么拿到毒牙
But how are we gonna get one of those things?
干嘛
What?
听说军中的咖啡香又浓
They say that in the army The coffee's mighty fine
看似泥巴水  味如松节油
It looks like muddy water And tastes like turpentine
我朝思暮想  但他们偏不让我走
Oh, Lord, I wanna go But they don't let me go
听说军中的男人高又壮
They say that in the army The men are mighty fine
钟楼怪人和科学怪人都比他们强
To me they look like hunchbacks And sound like Frankenstein
我朝思暮想  但他们偏不让我走
Oh, Lord, I wanna go But they won't let me go
快啊
Come on!
好  成功了
Yes! Got it!
下次你当诱饵
Next time, you're bait!
“游骑兵”
"Ranger."
That's me.
就是我
Ranger.
-游骑兵 -没错
Yeah. Yeah.
猎人
Hunter.
猎人  游骑兵
Hunter. Ranger.
-对 -猎人
- Yeah. - Hunter?
对
Yes.
魔鬼毡
Velcro.
-魔鬼毡  -对
Velcro. Yeah.
魔鬼毡…
Velcro. Velcro.
好了  够了…
Okay. All right, all right. That's enough. That's enough.
天啊
Oh, man.
它们真的很想进来
Really trying to get in here, huh?
这是你的家人
Is that your family?
你会回家见他们吗
Are you gonna see them? Are you gonna go home?
家
Home?
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
雄火龙
Rathalos.
上工了
Let's do this.
没事  走吧
Never mind. Let's go.
好了
Ready!
哇
Yeah!
那是什么 你得告诉我
What is that? You gotta tell me about that.
我可没有心理准备
You can't just do that to somebody.
差不多了
Any second now.
停下来
Stop!
诱饵
Bait!
“求生帐篷”
撑着点
Come on!
你们要保佑他
Watch over him!
不客气
You're welcome.
背甲龙
Apceros.
-背甲龙 -好
- Apceros. - Yeah.
好  它们吃草
Okay. Okay. They eat grass.
水…
Water. Water.
诱饵
Bait.
Bait?
你真搞笑
You're funny.
猜猜你下次快挂的时候  我会怎么做
Know what I'm gonna do next time you're dying in the desert?
啥都不做
Nothing.
好香
That smells good.
-砂龙 -我现在什么都肯吃
- Catch Cephalos. - I'll eat anything at this point.
家
Home.
是啊
Yeah. My way home.
希望那是我回家的路
I hope.
巧克力
Chocolate.
真好吃
So good.
那是什么
What's that?
好吧
All right.
-巧克力 -不…
Chocolate. No, no, no.
-巧克力 -这才不是巧克力
- Chocolate. - Not chocolate.
怎么回事
- What's going on?
雄火龙
- Rathalos.
你之前也说过  那到底是什么
You said that before. What the hell is a Rathalos?
谢谢你
Thank you.
先别谢我
Don't thank me yet.
看得开心吗
Enjoying the show?
什么
What?
-那是什么  -艾路
What is that? Palico.
我朋友说我误会你了
My friend tells me I misjudged you.
我搞不好还该向你道歉
I may even owe you an apology.
别指望了
Just don't hold your breath.
你为什么把我铐住 你在怕什么
Why did you put me in chains? What are you so afraid of?
你的世界…
Your world...
还有它对这世界的影响
and what it could do to mine.
你不是第一个传送过来的人
You aren't the first to cross over from your world.
很久以前就有别人来过
There were others. Long time ago.
所以你才会我的语言
That's how you speak my language?
我做了一番研究
- I made a study of it.
我为什么会来到这里
- What happened to me? How did I get here?
我们要找的答案可能就在这里
I believe that the answers we both seek lie here.
那个山顶上有座天塔
At the peak of that mountain lies the Sky Tower.
是一个古文明的遗迹
Remnants of an ancient civilization.
非常先进 危险
Very advanced. Very dangerous.
据说古人能在两个世界间来去自如
It is said that the Ancients knew how to travel between both worlds.
我认为那就是天塔的作用
I believe that is the purpose of the Sky Tower.
你也是这样过来的
That is what brought you here.
这个古文明出了什么事
What happened to this ancient civilization?
他们被自己的科技背叛  导致毁灭
They destroyed themselves. Their technology turned on them.
你认为这跟我的世界有关
You think my world had something to do with it.
没错
I suspect.
但开启两者间的大门曾经带来灾祸
But an open gateway between our two worlds was catastrophic once.
我想确保那再也不会发生
I intend to make sure that doesn't happen again.
我们在去调查天塔的路上
We were on our way to investigate the Sky Tower
误入角龙的地盘
when we strayed into the Diablos.
我跟朋友因此失散
That's where I lost my friend here.
当下只能先照顾伤者 修补船舰
Tending to the wounded and repairing the ship was our first priority.
现在我们要继续执行任务
But now we resume our mission.
古人的科技有最骇人的生物看守着…
The Ancients would guard their technology with the most fearsome of creatures,
雄火龙
a Rathalos.
几乎不可能杀死
Almost impossible to kill.
它们喷火前才会显露唯一的弱点
Their only weakness is just before they breathe fire.
你和我们一起战斗…
You help us with the battle ahead,
也许我们就能让你回家
perhaps we can help you get home.
怎么
What's the matter?
你们的世界没有猫吗
You don't have cats in your world?
嘿
Hey!
你又偷喝我的东西
You been drinking from my mug again?
破晓时出发  别让我等
We leave at dawn. And don't keep me waiting.
我讨厌等人
I hate waiting.
如何
So?
准备好了吗
You ready?
接下来的路可不好走
We got a hard climb ahead of us.
走吧
Come on!
我们认为是岩浆在驱动塔中的装置
We believe that the lava powers the machinery within the tower.
而它在控制风暴
It's controlling the storm.
没错
Exactly.
这生成了两个世界间的大门
It's creating a gateway to your world,
但似乎不太稳定
but it looks unstable.
走吧
Let's go.
雄火龙
Rathalos.
做好准备
Prepare yourself.
记住  它们喷火前才会显露弱点
Remember, they're weak just before they breathe fire.
丑八怪
Hey, ugly!
没事了  你安全了
It's okay! It's okay. You're safe now!
叫医护兵来
Get the medic!
“娜塔莉阿蒂米斯”
阿蒂米斯上尉
Captain Artemis?
把她抬上去
Let's get her inside!
抬起来
Up!
快走…
Let's go! Let's go!
上尉  我们一直在找你
Captain, we've been searching for you.
她穿的是什么
What the hell is she wearing?
红狼呼叫老鹰
Falcon Main, this is Red Wolf.
我们找到暗星了
We've made contact with Dark Star.
只有一名生还者
We have a lone survivor.
重复  只有一名生还者
I say again, a lone survivor.
-地面部队正在确保本区安全 -收到
Ground forces are securing the area. Copy that, Red Wolf.
上尉
Captain.
你听得到吗
Can you hear me?
上尉 阿蒂米斯上尉
Captain? Captain Artemis?
其他人呢
Where are the rest of your men?
-其他人  -是
- My men? - Yes.
A小队其他的成员
Where are the rest of Alpha Team?
收到
Copy that.
我们正遭到攻击
We're under attack!
瞄准腹部
Aim for the belly!
雄火龙
A Rathalos.
装弹
Load!
发射
Fire!
不…
No! No!
不要
No!
它朝我们来了
It's coming right for us!
快躲开
Evade!
“禁止踩踏”
天啊
My God.
来啊
Come on!
你输了
I got you.
我的朋友
My friend.
我还是不懂你在讲什么
Yeah, I still don't understand you, man.
对
Oh, yeah.
谢谢你
Yeah, thank you.
我没有巧克力了
I don't have any more chocolate.
接好
Think fast.
-你来了 -我们是来帮忙的
- You're here. - We came to help.
不能让我们的魔物攻击你的世界
We can't have monsters from my world attacking yours.
又开始了
It's starting again.
时间宝贵
We don't have much time.
另一波攻击要来了
There's going to be another attack.
我们必须回去
We have to get back.
我们得关闭天塔
We have to shut the Sky Tower down.
先想办法活命吧
- Let's try to live through this first.
收到
- Copy that.
怪物猎人
“别走开 精彩的还在后面”
改编自卡普电玩"怪物猎人"